Guide to the Ghassem Ghani collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- A The Letters of Am?r Kabir from No. 1 to 210., Series III
  - 74. Same to Same. Requesting a little time for an audience. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 75. Same to Same. Reporting that Moayer-al-Mamalik had visited the envoy. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 76. Same to Same. Concerning the procurrance of money. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 77. Same to Same. Concerning an audience. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 78. Same to Same. Concerning the dispatch of some letters with Hasan Ali Khan. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 79. Same to Same. Concerning the accounts of Azarbaijan's customs. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 80. Same to Same. Concerning a discussion with the minister (Russian) about Abbas Khan and Astarabad. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 81. Same to Same. Bringing two letters, written to two foreign minister's, to the attention of the Shah. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 82. Same to Same. Sending some letters in Persian to the Shah. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 83. Same to Same. Concerning some discussions with certain people. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 84. Same to Same. Concerning a copy of a letter. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 85. Same to Same. Sending the letters, which had been written to Hesam-os-Soltaneh, to the Shah. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 86. Same to Same. Informing the Shah that the letters of the envoys were full of attacks on him. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 87. Same to Same. Asking the Shah to approve the letter which is to be sent to the British Minister. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 88. Same to Same. Concerning Shah's health. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 89. Same to Same. Concerning Naval Morad Mirza and Iskandar Khan, and cursing intrigue. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 90. Amir Kabir to Naser-ed-Din Shah. Concerning the bad behavior of a soldier. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 91. Same to Same. Concerning the letters which are in the possession of Haji Ali Khan, and two other letters which are in his own possession. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 92. Same to Same. Concerning the favorable resolution of the Rasht problem. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 93. Same to Same. Concerning Sardaz and Mostofi al Mamalik who have to procure some money. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 94. Same to Same. Presenting the reply to the Minister's letter as was ordered by the Shah. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 95. Same to Same. A report on the activities of his office. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 96. Same to Same. Concerning his illness and uneasiness of the mind. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 97. Same to Same. Concerning his servitude to the Shah. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 98. Same to Same. Reporting the events of the day. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 99. Same to Same. Same. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 100. Same to Same. Sending a notebook for the Shah's perusal, which is then to be sent to the foreign ministers. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 101. Same to Same. Complaining about his life. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 102. Amir Kabir to Mehdi Khan Criticizing his behavior. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 103. Amir Kabir to Naser-ed-Din Shah. Concerning the time for an audience. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 104. Same to Same. Reporting the events of the day. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 105. Same to Same. Same. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 106. Same to Same. Concerning Musa Khan Qajar and Mirza Nabi Khan. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 107. Same to Same. Sending the letters written to Azarbaijan for the Shah's approval. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 108. Same to Same. Report of current affairs. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 109. Same to Same. Concerning the Armenians; that their request cannot be granted by the government. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 110. Same to Same. Expression of thanks to the Shah. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 111. Same to Same. Sending papers for approval. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 112. Same to Same. Report on current affairs. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 113. Same to Same. Same. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 114. Amir Kabir to Naser-ed-Din Shah. Report on current affairs. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 115. Same to Same. Announcing that the arsenal is ready for Shah's inspection. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 116. Same to Same. Sending Sepandar's letters. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 117. Same to Same. Sending the answer to Graf's (Count) letters. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 118. Same to Same. Report on current affairs. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 119. Same to Same. Concerning the Shah's mother. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 120. Same to Same. Sending letters for approval. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 121. Same to Same. Reporting that the book sent by Shah was read, and that it has no faults. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 122. Same to Same. Announcing that, the orders received will be compliment (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 123. Same to Same. Concerning Shah's horsebackriding. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 124. Same to Same. Inquiring about his health. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 125. Same to Same. Sending letters for approval. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 126. Same to Same. Rewriting the letter of the Russian minister. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 127. Same to Same. Report on current affairs. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 128. Same to Same. Concerning the Baghad question. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 129. Same to Same. Concerning letters received from Arabestan. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 130. Same to Same. Complaining of poor health. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 131. Same to Same. Sending the answer given to the foreign minister. The British minister asked for an audience to deliver the King's letter to the Shah. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 132. Same to Same. Complaining of intrigue and threat of some people. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 133. Same to Same. Concerning his sickness. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 134. Same to Same. Concerning the time of audience. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 135. Same to Same. Sending two money orders for signing. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 136. Same to Same. Concerning his majesty's health. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 137. Same to Same. Sending the letters of Prince Soltan Morad. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 138. Same to Same. Concerning Rashid Pasha's aggression on the Persian Borders; and inform ng the representatives of the mediating countries. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 139. Amir Kabir to Naser-ed-Din Shah. Sending the answer of the British minister about the passport. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 140. Same to Same. Sending the letters from Khorasan and Tabriz. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 141. Same to Same. Expressing regrets for inability to see Shah. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 142. Same to Same. Sending the instructions given to Khan-lar Mirza. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 143. Same to Same. Concerning the murder of Farrokl Khan. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 144. Same to Same. Report on current affairs. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 145. Same to Same. Same. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 146. Amir Kabir to Hesam-os-Saltaneh, governor of Fars. Concerning the construction of a fortress by Ya' qubali Khan's son. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 147. Amir Kabir to Naser-ed-Din Shah. Usual report. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 148. Same to Same. Same. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 149. Same to Same. Concerning Sam? Ajand?. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 150. Same to Same. Routine report. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 151. Same to Same. Sending letters from Russian and British ministers. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 152. Same to Same. A routine report. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 153. Same to Same. Concerning taking a fall from horse. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 154. Same to Same. Sending Hesam-os-Saltaneh's letters. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 155. Same to Same. Informing Shah that letters for Khorasan are ready. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 156. Same to Same. Concerning gift of dagger by Russian Emperor to Mohammad Hasan Khan Sardar. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 157. Same to Same. Reporting that the government building is finished. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 158. Same to Same. A Routine report. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 159. Same to Same. Sending letters. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 160. Same to Same. A Routine report. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 161. Same to Same. A Routine report. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 162. Same to Same. Concerning Gilan (province) and Isa Khan. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 163. Same to Same. Concerning negotiations with Russian minister and Mr. Thompson. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 164. Same to Same. A Routine report. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 165. Amir Kabir to Naser-ed-Din Shah. Concerning misbehavior of members of Azarbaijan regiment in Tehran. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 166. Same to Same. Concerning the theft of golden objects from the palace. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 167. Same to Same. Sending the procedures for getting passports. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 168. Same to Same. Sending accounts for signature. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 169. Same to Same. A Routine report. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 170. Same to Same. Concerning report of victories of the Persian Army. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 171. Same to Same. Concerning audience with Shah. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 172. Same to Same. Concerning the budget of the country. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 173. Same to Same. A Routine report. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 174. Same to Same. Concerning the translation of Moshie-od-Dowleh's letters, written in Turkey. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 175. Same to Same. A Routine report. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 176. Same to Same. Thanking the Shah for his kindness. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 177. Same to Same. A Routine report. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 178. Same to Same. Same (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 179. Same to Same. Concerning the booklet about Tehran. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 180. Same to Same. Sending the report about the victories of the Persian Army (in Khorasan) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 181. Same to Same. Concerning the answers received from Vazir Nezam and Emam Gom'eh and Hamzeh Mirza's replies. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 182. Same to Same. Informing the Shah that the enclosed letter has been brought by the Russian minister and he wants an answer by tomorrow. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 183. Same to Same. A Routine report. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 184. Same to Same. Sending letters received from provinces. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 185. Same to Same. Concerning Ahmad Khan's report from Tifl?s and the answer to his report. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 186. Same to Same. Concerning Ahmad Khan' Dar?k and J?ek. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 187. Amir Kabir to Naser-ed-Din Shah. Asking the Shah to order Mo'ayer-ol-MÄmalek to greet the new Russian envoy. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 188. Same to Same. A routine report. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 189. Same to Same. Same. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 190. Same to Same. Same. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 191. Same to Same. Concerning the reception in the court. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 192. Same to Same. Sending the order issued to Tahmaeb Mirza. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 193. Same to Same. Concerning book on drill and exercises. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 194. Same to Same. Concerning discussion with a few officials and merchants. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 195. Same to Same. Concerning the occupation of the government citadel by the government forces. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 196. Same to Same. A routine report. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 197. Same to Same. Sending the letter Addressed to the Russian minister about Bandar Jaz (on margin the handwriting of the Shah) approving the letter) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 198. Same to Same. Concerning the taxation of Kurdistan. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 199. Same to Same. Thanking the Shah for his benevolence. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 200. Same to Same. Concerning victories of the government forces in Mashhad. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 201. Same to Same. Recommending Afshar for governor of Damghan and SemnÄn. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 202. Same to Same. Concerning building expenditures. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 203. Same to Same. Concerning the audience of one of the foreign representatives. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 204. Same to Same. Informing the Shah that there are not sufficient funds for the Gorgan's army's expedition. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 205. Same to Same. Sending letters for inspection (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 206. Same to Same. Regretting that he could not see the Shah. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 207. Same to Same. Sending replies to Saham-od-Dowleh for Shah's inspection. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 208. Same to Same. A routine report. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 209. Same to Same. Concerning negotiations with the foreign ministers. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 210. Same to Same. Informing the Shah about his meeting with the Russian and the British Ministers and about their desire for an audience with Shah. (Box 1, Folder 16)
- SERIES IV
  - 1. An order of Naser-ed-Din Shah, dated Shaval, 1287 A.H. Rewarding Mirza Abdul Vahab Khan, Vice Governor of Gilan, for his services. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 2. Naser-ed-Din Shah to Aziz Khan Sardar Kol. dated 15 Shaban 1278 A.H. Concerning the appointment of Mirza Abdul Vahab Khan to the post of the representative of the Foreign Ministry in Azarbaijan. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 3. Naser-ed-Din Shah to Mirza Abdul Vahab Khan-Vice Governor of Gilan, dated Gamadi-ol-ula 1287 A.H. Concerning the collection of taxes. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 4. Naser-ed-Din Shah to Aziz Khan Sardar Kol, dated Shaban 1278 A.H. Same as No. 2. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 5. Same to Same, dated 29 Shaban 1278, A.H. Concerning the donation of several villages to Mirza Abdul Vahab Khan. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 6. An order of Naser-ed-Din Shah, dated Ramazan 1278 A.H. Giving a gold medal to Mirza Abdul Vahab Khan. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 7. A telegram from Astarabad to Naser-ed-Din Shah dated Zulkadah 1297 A.H. Concerning the punishment of bandits. In the margin the handwriting of the Shah. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 8. Nasir-od-Dowleh to Naser-ed-Din Shah. Expressing his happiness that the Shah did not get hurt when he fell from his horse. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 9. An order of Naser-ed-Din Shah, dated Shaban 1281 A.H. Giving a jobbeh (overcoat) to Mirza Abdul Vahab Khan. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 10. A copy of the letter of Hamzeh Aqa to Sheikh Abdullah. Concerning a skirmish around the village of Banar (near the Turks-Persian frontier). (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 11. A marriage certificate. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 12. A pledge of the Sabzevar confectioners, dated 1317 A.H. Concerning the closing of stores on Fridays. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 13. A document, concerning a donation, signed by several priests, dated 1310 A.H. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 14. A letter of attorney, dated 9 Rabi-ol-Avol 1241 A.H. Concerning the administration of some estates in Kermanshah. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 15. An order. Concerning the establishment of a committee of merchants, dated Rajab 1294 A.H. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 16. A copy of an order of Shah Abbas Safavi. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 17. Naser-ed-Din Shah to Aziz Khan Sardar Kol, dated Rajab 1282 A.H. Concerning a complaint by the Russian government about the escape of some bandits from Russia to Iran, and the request for their capture and surrender to the Russian government. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 18. A complaint of the residents of Talegan concerning the abuses of Nayeb. In the margin the handwriting of Naser-ed-Din Shah, ordering Sepahsalar to look into the matter. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 19. An order of Naser-ed-Din Shah, dated Jamadi-os-Sani 1283 A.H. Giving a jobbeh (overcoat) to Abdul Vahab Khan. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 20. The same. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 21. An order of Naser-ed-Din Shah, dated Moharam 1285 A.H. Concerning the appointment of Mirza Abdul Vahab Khan to ruler of Savojbolagh. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 22. Naser-ed-Din Shah to Mirza Abdul Vahab Khan, dated Ramazan 1287 A.H. Concerning two merchants who have started the building of a highway. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 23. An order of Naser-ed-Din Shah, dated Rabi-ol-Akhar 1287 A.H. Giving a jobbeh (overcoat) to Abdul Vahab Khan. (Box 2, Folder 17)
- SERIES V
  - 1. Mirza Said Khan (Minister of Foreign Affairs) to Moshir-od-Dowleh, Ambassador to Turkey. Dated 15 Ramazan 1286 A.H. Concerning Mirza Hussein Ali (Bahan'llah) and requesting the Turkish government to put greater restriction on him. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - 2. The views of Doctor Tolouzon (the physician of Naser-ed-Din Shah) on the health committee. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - 3. Mirza Said Khan to Moshir-od-Dowleh Concerning the progress of Turkey and the backwardness of Iran. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - 4. Same to Same: dated Ramazan, 1279 A.H. Concerning Mirza Musa and his complaint of Mirza Bozorg. (Persian representative in Baghdad) (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - 5. Same to Same. dated Ramazan, 1279 A.H. Concerning the mistreatment of the Persian citizens by the Turkish government. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - 6. Same to Same. dated Ramazan 1279 A.H. Concerning the increase in the number of Mirza Hussein Ali's (Bahan'llah) followers in Baghdad, and the necessity of their destruction. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - 7. Same to Same. dated 1287 A.H. Concerning Abbas Mirza and his mistreatment by the Turks. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - 8. Same to Same, dated 12 Rajab 1286 A.H. Concerning Mirza Badi who has brought a letter from Bahau'llah for Naser-ed-Din Shah. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - 9. Same to Same. dated 1286 A.H. Concerning the health committee. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - 10. Same to Same. dated 28 Jamadi-al-ula, 1288 A.H. Concerning Abbas Mirza who had escaped from Iran to Turkey and had been received by the Sultan. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - 11. Same to Same. Concerning the health committee. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - 12. Same to Same. dated Rajab, 1286 Concerning a letter which was brought to the Shah from Mirza Hussein Ali (Baha'u'llah) and requesting that the Turkish government be more severe with the prisoner. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - 13. Same to Same dated 1286 A.H. Concerning the mistreatment of Persian pilgrims by Turkish officials. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - 14. A report from Baghdad, concerning the above matter (no. 13) (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - 15. A copy of an order by Naser-ed-Din Shah concerning (No.13) (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - 16. Mirza Said Khan to Moshir-od-Dowleh. dated 14 Rabi-ol-Aval 1287 A.H. Concerning cholera in Iran and the health committee. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - 17. Same to Same. dated 18 Jamadi-ol-ala 1286 A.H. Concerning the newspaper La Turk, and an article criticizing Iran. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - 18. Same to Same. dated 18 Jamadi-ol-ula, 1286 A.H. Concerning the trip of Esmail Pasha the Khadive of Egypt and the rivalry of France and England over the Suez Canal. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - 19. Same to Same. dated Rabi-ol-Sani 1286. Concerning the take over of Qari Qaleh and the dispersal of the rebellious Turkamans. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - 20. Same to Same. dated Rabi-ol-Aval, 1279 A.H. Concerning the appointment of Seyyed Hussein to the post of the supervisor and key holder to the shrine of Abbas. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - 21. Same to Same. dated 19 Shaval, 1278 Concerning the trip of Malcam Khan from Iran to Iraq. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 22. Same to Same. dated Shaval 1276 Concerning the giving of a medal to Moshir-ol-Dowleh. In the margin handwriting of the Shah. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 23. Same to Same. dated 8 Jamadi-ol-Aval 1279 A.H. Concerning the mistreatment of Persian citizens by Turkish officials. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 24. Mirza Said Khan to Mirza Ahmad Khan (Persian chargé d'affair in Turkey) dated 26 Jamadi, 1285 A.H. Concerning the measures taken by the Turkish government against the Babis. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 25. Same to Same. dated 1 Jamadi, 1279 A.H. Concerning Mirza Malkam Khan and the Shah's praise of him. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 26. Same to Same. 22 Shabam, 1284 A.H. Concerning dissent between Mirza Hussein Ali (Baha'u'llah) and Mirza Yahya and attempts by some Bahais on the life of the Persian chargé d'affair. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 27. Same to Same. 11 Shaval, 1284 A.H. Concerning the oppression of the Persian citizens by Nameq Pasha. (Turkish governor of Iraq in Baghdad) (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 28. Same to Same. dated 1285 A.H. Concerning some current affairs, i.e. of demarcation of boundaries between Turkey & Iran and the abolition of the quarantine. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 29. Mirza Said Khan to Moshir-ad-Dowleh dated Ramazan, 1278 A.H. Concerning the trip of Naser-ed-Din Shah to Saltaneh and the concern of the Turkish government. (In the margin the handwriting of the Shah). (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 30. Same to Same. dated Gamadi-al-Sani, 1281 A.H. Concerning talks with All Pasha (Turkish minister of Foreign Affairs) about Mirza Hussein Ali (Baha 'u'llah) (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 31. Same to Same. dated Rabi-ol-Aval 1287 A.H. Concerning Il Khani. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 32. Same to Same. dated 22 Ziqadeh 1297 A.H. Concerning Sheikh Ofeidullah and his intention of uniting the Kurds of Turkey and Iran and organizing an independent Kurdish government. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 33. Moshir-od-Dowleh to Mirza Ahmad Iran's charged'affair in Turkey. dated 4 Ziqadeh 1289 A.H. Concerning an occurrence in Khan Valedeh (Constantinople) and the arrest of some Persians, and stating that if the Turkish government does not take steps to punish those who arrested them, Naser-ed-Din Shah's trip to Turkey will be cancelled. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 34. An order of Naser-ed-Din Shah: dated Ramazan 1279 A.H. Concerning the furniture of the Persian embassy in Turkey. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 35. Turkish embassy to the Persian foreign ministry: dated Ramazan, 1301 A.H. Concerning an exhibition in Antwirp Belgium. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 36. A copy of the letter of Heydar Effendi to the Persian foreign ministry. dated Jamadi-ol-Sani 1279 A.H. Concerning the rebirth of the tradition of killing an effigy of Omar in Iran. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 37. Mirza Said Khan to Moshir-od-Dowleh, dated. Rajab 1276 A.H. Concerning an order of one war ship from America. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 38. Same to Same. Concerning the above. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 39. From the Persian Embassy in Turkey to the Persian agent in Baghdad. dated 15 Rabial-Sani, 1276 A.H. Concerning the Bah'ais and measures to exile them to Iran. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 40. The Persian Foreign Ministry to Moshir-od-Dowleh dated 16 Safar, 1276 A.H. Concerning the concentration of Bah'ais in Karbola. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 41. Same to Same. dated 1 Shafan, 1276 A.H. Concerning a permit to go to Mecca. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 42. Naser-ed-Din Shah to Mirza Said Khan, Foreign minister: dated 1279 A.H. Concerning the conquest of Herat by Doust Mohammad Khan, and the view of the Persian government on Herat. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 43. Mirza Said Khan to Moshir-od-Dowleh: A friendly letter. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 44. Naser-ed-Din Shah to Mirza Said Khan: Concerning the relations of the Persian government with the British ambassador. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 45. Haji Molla Ali to Naser-ed-Din Shah. Concerning Hadji Ali Aqa and his attempts on the lives of Mullas in Baghdad. In the margin Naser-ed-Din Shah's order to take necessary steps immediately. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 46. A copy of the letter of Naser-ed-Din Shah to the Foreign Minister: Concerning Abbas Mirza, who has gone to Istanbul, and has been accepted by the Sultan. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 47. Sepahsalar (Moshir-od-Dowleh) to Sheikh Mohsen Khan, Persian ambassador to Turkey. A friendly letter. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 48.-49. Same to Same. A friendly letter. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 50. Mirza Said Khan to Moin-ol-Molk, Persian ambassador to Turkey, dated 21 Ramazan 1303 A.H. Concerning the mistreatment of Persian citizens by Turkish officials in Iraq. In the margin the handwriting of Naser-ed-Din Shah. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 51. Moshir-od-Dowleh to the Persian embassy in Turkey: dated 1303 A.H. Concerning Hadji Mirza Hassan Shirazi (a famous Spiritual leader) who was insulted in Samereh (Iraq). (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 52. Moshir-od-Dowleh to Mirza Mohsen Khan, (Persian ambassador to England.) dated 8 Ziqadeh, 1286 A.H. Concerning the concentration of Russian forces in Qezel-Su. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 53. Moshir-od-Dowleh from Meshed to Mirza Yahya Khan (his brother) Persian ambassador to England. Concerning Herat and Doust Mohammad Khan's surrounding of it. (Box 2, Folder 20)